file.net 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy

We respect your privacy. We don't collect email addresses. We don't send out spam.

### Who Are We?

File.net, an open forum for sharing information about files, is one of the oldest sites on the Web dedicated to communicating detailed, carefully vetted information about the principal files used in software that runs on Microsoft Windows.

15 years ago, we were among the first experts to analyze and classify Windows files according to their properties and behavior. Nowadays, our analysis tools are used all over the world by anti-virus software publishers, the military, government agencies, and law enforcement, and for special projects.

We have been members of the Association of Shareware Professionals since 1998. We also develop educational software for the blind and visually impaired, and take part in a variety of charitable activities.

### Introduction

Personal data (usually referred to just as "data" below) will only be processed by us to the extent necessary and for the purpose of providing a functional and user-friendly website, including its contents, and the services offered there.

Per Art. 4 No. 1 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679, i.e. the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter referred to as the "GDPR"), "processing" refers to any operation or set of operations such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation, alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, or otherwise making available, alignment, or combination, restriction, erasure, or destruction performed on personal data, whether by automated means or not.

The following privacy policy is intended to inform you in particular about the type, scope, purpose, duration, and legal basis for the processing of such data either under our own control or in conjunction with others. We also inform you below about the third-party components we use to optimize our website and improve the user experience which may result in said third parties also processing data they collect and control.

Our privacy policy is structured as follows:

I. Information about us as controllers of your data  
II. The rights of users and data subjects  
III. Information about the data processing

### I. Information about us as controllers of your data

The party responsible for this website (the "controller") for purposes of data protection law is:  

### II. The rights of users and data subjects

With regard to the data processing to be described in more detail below, users and data subjects have the right

  * to confirmation of whether data concerning them is being processed, information about the data being processed, further information about the nature of the data processing, and copies of the data (cf. also Art. 15 GDPR);
  * to correct or complete incorrect or incomplete data (cf. also Art. 16 GDPR);
  * to the immediate deletion of data concerning them (cf. also Art. 17 DSGVO), or, alternatively, if further processing is necessary as stipulated in Art. 17 Para. 3 GDPR, to restrict said processing per Art. 18 GDPR;
  * to receive copies of the data concerning them and/or provided by them and to have the same transmitted to other providers/controllers (cf. also Art. 20 GDPR);
  * to file complaints with the supervisory authority if they believe that data concerning them is being processed by the controller in breach of data protection provisions (see also Art. 77 GDPR).

In addition, the controller is obliged to inform all recipients to whom it discloses data of any such corrections, deletions, or restrictions placed on processing the same per Art. 16, 17 Para. 1, 18 GDPR. However, this obligation does not apply if such notification is impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. Nevertheless, users have a right to information about these recipients.

**Likewise, under Art. 21 GDPR, users and data subjects have the right to object to the controller's future processing of their data pursuant to Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. In particular, an objection to data processing for the purpose of direct advertising is permissible.**

### III. Information about the data processing

Your data processed when using our website will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose for its storage ceases to apply, provided the deletion of the same is not in breach of any statutory storage obligations or unless otherwise stipulated below.

#### Server data

For technical reasons, the following data sent by your internet browser to us or to our server provider will be collected, especially to ensure a secure and stable website: These server log files record the type and version of your browser, operating system, the website from which you came (referrer URL), the webpages on our site visited, the date and time of your visit, as well as the IP address from which you visited our site.

The data thus collected will be temporarily stored, but not in association with any other of your data.

The basis for this storage is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in the improvement, stability, functionality, and security of our website.

The data will be deleted within no more than seven days, unless continued storage is required for evidentiary purposes. In which case, all or part of the data will be excluded from deletion until the investigation of the relevant incident is finally resolved.

#### Cookies

##### a) Session cookies

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files or other storage technologies stored on your computer by your browser. These cookies process certain specific information about you, such as your browser, location data, or IP address.  

This processing makes our website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure, allowing us, for example, to display our website in different languages or to offer a shopping cart function.

The legal basis for such processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR, insofar as these cookies are used to collect data to initiate or process contractual relationships.

If the processing does not serve to initiate or process a contract, our legitimate interest lies in improving the functionality of our website. The legal basis is then Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

When you close your browser, these session cookies are deleted.

##### b) Third-party cookies

If necessary, our website may also use cookies from companies with whom we cooperate for the purpose of advertising, analyzing, or improving the features of our website.

Please refer to the following information for details, in particular for the legal basis and purpose of such third-party collection and processing of data collected through cookies.

##### c) Disabling cookies

You can refuse the use of cookies by changing the settings on your browser. Likewise, you can use the browser to delete cookies that have already been stored. However, the steps and measures required vary, depending on the browser you use. If you have any questions, please use the help function or consult the documentation for your browser or contact its maker for support. Browser settings cannot prevent so-called flash cookies from being set. Instead, you will need to change the setting of your Flash player. The steps and measures required for this also depend on the Flash player you are using. If you have any questions, please use the help function or consult the documentation for your Flash player or contact its maker for support.

If you prevent or restrict the installation of cookies, not all of the functions on our site may be fully usable.

#### Contact

If you contact us via email or the contact form, the data you provide will be used for the purpose of processing your request. We must have this data in order to process and answer your inquiry; otherwise we will not be able to answer it in full or at all.

The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

Your data will be deleted once we have fully answered your inquiry and there is no further legal obligation to store your data, such as if an order or contract resulted therefrom.

#### User posts, comments, and ratings

We offer you the opportunity to post questions, answers, opinions, and ratings on our website, hereinafter referred to jointly as "posts." If you make use of this opportunity, we will process and publish your post, the date and time you submitted it, and any pseudonym you may have used.

The legal basis for this is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a) GDPR. You may revoke your prior consent under Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR with future effect. All you have to do is inform us that you are revoking your consent.

In addition, we will also process your IP address and email address. The IP address is processed because we might have a legitimate interest in taking or supporting further action if your post infringes the rights of third parties and/or is otherwise unlawful.

In this case, the legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in any legal defense we may have to mount.

#### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics on our website. This is a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (hereinafter: Google).

Through certification according to the EU-US Privacy Shield

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)

Google guarantees that it will follow the EU's data protection regulations when processing data in the United States.

The Google Analytics service is used to analyze how our website is used. The legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in the analysis, optimization, and economic operation of our site.

Usage and user-related information, such as IP address, place, time, or frequency of your visits to our website will be transmitted to a Google server in the United States and stored there. However, we use Google Analytics with the so-called anonymization function, whereby Google truncates the IP address within the EU or the EEA before it is transmitted to the US.

The data collected in this way is in turn used by Google to provide us with an evaluation of visits to our website and what visitors do once there. This data can also be used to provide other services related to the use of our website and of the internet in general.

Google states that it will not connect your IP address to other data. In addition, Google provides further information with regard to its data protection practices at

including options you can exercise to prevent such use of your data.

In addition, Google offers an opt-out add-on at

in addition with further information. This add-on can be installed on the most popular browsers and offers you further control over the data that Google collects when you visit our website. The add-on informs Google Analytics' JavaScript (ga.js) that no information about the website visit should be transmitted to Google Analytics. However, this does not prevent information from being transmitted to us or to other web analytics services we may use as detailed herein.

#### Shariff social media buttons

Our website uses the plug-ins of the following social networks. To integrate these plug-ins, we use the Shariff plug-in.

The legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in improving the quality of our website.

Shariff is an open source program developed by c't and heise. By integrating this plug-in, linked graphics prevent the following social network plug-ins from automatically establishing a connection to the respective social networks server when you visit website(s) on which the plug-ins are integrated. Only if you click on one of these linked graphics will you be forwarded to the service of the respective social network. Only then will information about your use of our site be recorded by the respective social network. This information may include your IP address, the date and time you visited our site, as well as the pages you viewed.

If you are logged in to one of the social network services while visiting one of our plugged-in websites, the information collected by the plug-in from your specific visit will be recognized by the provider of that social network and assigned to your personal user account there and/or publish information about your interaction with our site there. If, for example, you use the a share button for the social network, this information may be stored in your user account there and published on the platform of the respective social network provider. To prevent this, you must either log out of the social network before clicking the graphic or make the appropriate settings in your social network account.

Further information about Shariff is available at

[http://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html](https://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html)

The following social networks are integrated into our website:

**Facebook** operated by Facebook Inc, 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, operated within the EU by Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. 

Privacy information can be found at <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

Through certification according to the EU-US Privacy Shield

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)

Facebook guarantees that it will follow the EU's data protection regulations when processing data in the United States.

**Twitter** operated by Twitter Inc, 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA.

Privacy information can be found at <https://twitter.com/privacy>

Through certification according to the EU-US Privacy Shield

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active)

Twitter guarantees that it will follow the EU's data protection regulations when processing data in the United States.

#### Google AdSense

We use Google AdSense on our website to integrate advertisements. This is a service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (hereinafter: Google).

Through certification according to the EU-US Privacy Shield

[https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)

Google guarantees that it will follow the EU's data protection regulations when processing data in the United States.

Google AdSense stores cookies and web beacons on your device via your browser. This enables Google to analyze how you use our website. In addition to your IP address and the advertising formats displayed, the information thus collected will be transmitted to Google in the USA and stored there. Google may also share this information with third parties. Google states that it will not connect your IP address to other data.

The legal basis is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest lies in the analysis, optimization, and economic operation of our site.

If you do not agree to this processing, you have the option of preventing the installation of cookies by making the appropriate settings in your browser. Further details can be found in the section about cookies above.

In addition, Google offers an opt-out add-on at <https://policies.google.com/privacy> and <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated> in particular on options for preventing the use of data.

#### AddThis

We may still use the bookmarking service AddThis, 1900 Oracle Way, Reston, VA 20190, (703) 478-9000, USA as authorized by our legitimate interest under Article 6, Paragraph 1 (f.) of the GDPR, in allowing our visitors to share our pages and make ourselves known. AddThis collects pseudonymous information transmitted by the browser, creates anonymous user profiles and uses them for customized marketing. For this AddThis sets a browser cookie. You can disagree under [http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out) (Opt-Out). AddThis’ data privacy policy can be found at: [http://www.addthis.com/privacy](https://www.addthis.com/privacy)

#### Cloudflare

We use the CDN (Content Delivery Network) and SSL encryption protocoll (https) by Cloudflare, Inc., 101 Townsend St, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA as authorized by our legitimate interest under Article 6, Paragraph 1 (f.) of the GDPR, in allowing our visitors to view our pages quickly and securely. Cloudflare provides its own servers and infrastructure for this purpose. Through certification by the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnZKAA0&status=Active) Cloudflare guarantees that the EU data protection requirements will be observed even when data are processed in the USA. Cloudflare’s data privacy policy can be found at: <https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/>

#### Contacting us

If you have any questions, just email us.

This Privacy Policy is effective as of June 19, 2018. The Privacy Policy Statement was provided by the [Law Offices of Weiß & Partner](https://www.ratgeberrecht.eu/leistungen/muster-datenschutzerklaerung.html). We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy.
